要想建造横贯大陆的铁路
To build the transcontinental railroad,
"大佬"托马斯·杜兰特曾经说过
Thomas "Doc" Durant once said
一个人必须面对心中的恶魔  然后摧毁它们
"A man must face his demons and destroy them
否则就会受其影响  无所作为
or become undone by them."
1868年的地狱之轮可不是这些人该待的地方
The hell on wheels of 1868 is no place for bashful men,
害羞  轻信和无把握之人
the deluded, or unassured.
以及邋遢鬼  穿着圣服的醉鬼和疯子
No place for sloppy men, drunk and disorderly in their heavenly vestments
他们的半只脚已踏进坟墓
on their way to an early grave.
过去三年里  铁路通过火车
The railroad has contained the west these last three years,
和铺在地上的铁轨控制了西部
with its iron horse and rails pinned to the ground.
日复一日  即使它没有带来礼仪
And each passing day brings with it civilization,
也带来了文明
if not civility.
穿着制服的文明人们  如今用钢笔做着
And men in suits, who do now with their pens
之前粗鲁的人们用枪做的事
what earlier, rougher men did with their guns.
卡伦·博汉南  联太公司前任总工程师
Cullen Bohannon, late of the Union Pacific,
更像个枪手  而不是文明人
is more gunman than suit.
他回到了夏安镇  如今它被称为
His return to Cheyenne; these days referred to
平原上的魔幻城镇
as the "Magic city of the plains,"
他在草原上消失了几个月  人们以为他死了
after months lost to the prairie and presumed dead,
现在却带着摩门妻儿归来
with a Mormon wife and child in tow,
他也许正是我们所需的润滑剂
might be just the grease we need
来推动全国痴迷的铁路建设
to turn the wheels of our national obsession,
让漫长的冬季随雪消融
buried these long winter months in snow
由泥土中的车辙决定未来
and now, up to its wheel-wells in mud.
或者说  这是他自我牺牲的开始
Or might it be the match strike of self-immolation?
因为博汉南先生一贯的正直
For Mr. Bohannon has always worn his integrity
亦是他的负担
like a millstone around his neck.
好啊
Howdy.
要帮忙吗
Help you?
你可以让开
You can step aside.
博汉南回来了
Bohannon's back!
-你来这里干什么  -不关你的事
- What's your business here? - None of your business.
你听到了吗  警官
Ha. You hear that, deputy?
这不关我们的事
It's none of our business.
摩门教徒在这里只会遇上麻烦  朋友
There's nothin' here for Mormons but trouble, friend.
我不是来找麻烦的
I ain't lookin' for trouble.
在我的镇上  麻烦刚好就会找这种人
Just the kind of people trouble finds in my town.
西北部五六十英里有摩门教徒的聚居地
There's a Mormon settlement 50, 60 miles to the northwest.
你们在那边会受到欢迎的
You'll be welcome there.
放开我的马
Let go of my horse.
别碰我
Don't touch me.
你最好听她的
I'd listen to her.
我建议你转过身来
I suggest you turn around and--
他还是挡了我的路
Still blockin' my horse.
谢谢
Thank you.
驾
Let's go.
卡伦·博汉南回来了  亲爱的读者们
Cullen Bohannon has come home, dear reader.
在这个文明世界以西的小镇里
And in our little world just west of civilization,
我们发现自己又一次任他摆布
we find ourselves once again at his mercy.
你是说  挖一条
Are you telling me it's impossible
穿山隧道是不可能的吗  没人能做到
to tunnel through that mountain? No man can do it?
我们已经炸了一周多了
We've been blastin' for more than a week.
该死的山一直坍塌
Damn thing keeps caving in on itself.
天啊  德莱尼
God sakes, Delaney.
内华达山脉没挡住亨廷顿
The Sierra Nevadas couldn't stop Huntington.
这个小山丘也不能阻挡我
This blip of a molehill is not going to stop me.
内华达山脉由花岗岩组成  杜兰特先生
The Sierras are made of granite, Mr. Durant.
这里的岩层更不稳定
We're dealing with more unstable terrain here.
泥岩和页岩
Mudrock and shale.
借口可不会帮我建好隧道
Excuses will not get my tunnel built.
你尽一切努力吧
Now, do whatever you have to do.
让工人加班清除碎石
Put on an extra shift to clear the rubble
印更多代金券付给他们
and print up more scrip to pay the men.
他们不会白白干活的  被自由人也不会
They won't work for nothing, not even the freedmen.
杜兰特先生...
Mr. Durant--
就这样  谢谢  德莱尼
That will be all. Thank you, Delaney.
这里是铁路办公室
This is the railroad office,
不是售票厅
not the ticket office.
售票厅在后面
Behind the building.
铁轨对面的车站那边
Across the tracks at the depot.
我是卡伦·博汉南  来见杜兰特
Cullen Bohannon. Here to see Durant.
我是马丁·德莱尼
Martin Delaney.
石溪大桥建造者
Builder of stone and brook bridges.
联合太平洋铁路首席工程师
Chief engineer at the Union Pacific.
卡伦·博汉南的鬼魂来了
It's the ghost of Cullen Bohannon.
现在竟然是摩门教徒
And...Mormon, no less.
如果有证据表明你无法被杀死
If ever there was proof that you cannot be killed,
那这就是了
this is it.
上次我看到你时  你正被一群蒙面歹徒
The last time I saw you, you were being dragged away
拖走  此后便再无踪迹
by a gang of masked outlaws, never to be seen again.
带我走的是她爸爸
It was her dad who took me.
摩门民兵因为...
Mormon militia on account of the--
这是我妻子娜奥米  我儿子威廉
This is my wife Naomi and, uh, my son William.
我们在史密斯保卫站过的冬
We wintered up at Fort Smith.
虽然出了些事  不过我现在回来了
Took some doin', but I'm back now.
那你为了逃出来  杀害了多少
And how many Mormons did you have to put in the ground
摩门教徒
to effect your escape?
不是那样的
Wasn't like that.
你总是那样  博汉南
It's always like that with you, Bohannon.
你在我的镇上引发了一场枪战
You start a gunfight in my town,
差点把我们都害死  为什么
nearly have us all killed, and for what?
就因为一个被你搞大肚子的姑娘
A girl you got pregnant.
我是回来工作的  我能恢复原职吗
Come back for my old job. Is it mine or not?
不  不能
No. Not.
你的铁路停滞不前  杜兰特
Your railroad's stuck, Durant.
只有我才能让它再继续前进
I'm the only one who can get it movin' again.
即使我可以解雇德莱尼先生
Even if I could fire Mr. Delaney,
他也没做错什么事  不应受此待遇
he has done nothing to warrant it.
可是你呢  站在那里
You, on the other hand, stand there wallowing
道德沦丧  还刚刚亲口承认
in moral turpitude, having just confessed
自己根本没有建造铁路所需要的
to complete lack of regard for the most basic fundamental
最基本的品质
needed to get this road moving:
为人可靠
dependability.
你要想继续建造铁路
What you need to get this road movin' again
就需要一个能让你翻过谢尔曼峰的人
is a man who can get you over Sherman Summit, all right?
而他做不到
He ain't him.
我不是要翻过去  博汉南
I am not going over, Bohannon.
我要穿过去
I am going through.
而且不用你的帮助
And without you.
欢迎来到夏安镇  女士
Welcome to Cheyenne, madam.
事情不像我计划的那么顺利
This ain't how I planned on things goin'.
夏安镇也不像我想象中那么美好
This ain't how I pictured Cheyenne.
我会想办法的
I'll figure it out.
我们一起想办法
We'll figure it out together.
上车吧
Come on.
博汉南先生
Mr. Bohannon!
你的到来真是雪中送炭啊
You are a sight for sore eyes.
刚好在我以为自己的好运用完的时候
Just when I thought me luck had run out,
你就来了
here you be.
你这是怎么了
What happened to you?
我跟一个摩门教的姑娘结婚了
Got a Mormon girl in the family way,
现在需要一份工作
and I need a job.
还有什么问题吗
Any more questions?
格兰特派了个投机之人
Grant sent a carpetbagger out
来这里实行法律维护秩序
to install law and order.
他绞死了一个我赌场里面的人
He hung a man from the rafters of my casino.
我现在正需要一个你这样的人
I could use a man like you.
不了  谢谢
No, thanks.
你刚才不是说需要一份工作吗
You just said you needed a job.
不是那种工作
Not that one.
很高兴见到你  米奇
It was good to see you, Mick.
对了  我现在是镇长了
By the way, I'm the mayor now!
恭喜了
Congratulations.
他是你的好友吗
Is he a close friend of yours?
他杀了自己的兄弟  是我帮他埋的
Killed his brother, and I helped to bury him.
这样我们应该算有点交情吧
Suppose that makes us somethin'.
这杆枪可花了我28美元
I paid $28 for this rifle.
你可以去找他报仇
You can take it out of his hide.
什么时候
When?
我让你去的时候
When I tell you.
这个保加利亚人不简单
A rare Bulgarian, that one.
可以不知不觉就把你眼皮子地下的东西偷走
Steal the milk out your tea as soon as he look at ya.
是联合太平洋铁路公司的测量师
A surveyor for the Union Pacific.
杜兰特先生的雇员
An employee of Mr. Durant
刚好也是我赌场的
who happens to be a partner
一个合作伙伴
in my casino.
他臭了
He stinks.
把他弄走
Get him out of here.
你们自己弄吧
I'll leave that to you.
把他弄走  麦克吉尼斯
Get him out of here, McGinnes.
他现在是你们的烂摊子了
He's your trash now.
下次你们再在我的地盘
And next time ye decide to turn my business
绞死人...
into a gallows...
走之前给我清理干净
you clean up before you leave.
两位  告辞
Gentlemen.
吁
Ho.
你来吃午饭吗
You coming to lunch?
你的东西
This yourn.
早知道你会回来  我就不动
I knowed you's comin' back, I'd have guarded
藏在东西里的那些钱了
what little money was hid backside and front.
那可让我们改善了一个月伙食
That money fed us good for a month.
还好好喝了一顿
Bought us one hell of a hangover, too.
你帮我找个工作  钱就不计较了
If you give me a job, we'll forget about the money.
你可不是黑人  博汉南先生
You ain't been in the sun long enough for that, Mr. Bohannon.
我有家要养
I got a family to feed.
跟我干  报酬和黑人一样
Freedman work, freedman wages.
很公平
Fair enough.
从没想过我有天能成头儿的头儿
Never thought I'd see the day I'd be the boss of the boss.
别高兴太早  帕萨姆
Don't get used to it, Psalms.
露丝
Ruth.
我正想去找你呢
I was just on my way to see you now.
今天我们都吓到了  是不是
We all got the shock of our lives today, didn't we?
博汉南先生回到夏安镇了
W-With Mr. Bohannon's return to Cheyenne.
是的
Yes.
这几个月我都在祈祷他回来
I've been praying these many months for such a miracle.
你还好吗  露丝
How are you, Ruth?
依然在祈祷
Still praying.
你住在这  应该没人会找麻烦
Reckon nobody'll start a war if you stay here.
挺好的
It'll do just fine.
给
Here.
吃吧
Eat.
好  我抱
Yeah, there we go.
听着
Now.
遇到麻烦  可以去找牧师
You have trouble on the way, you can see church lady.
她叫露丝  会帮你的
Her name's Ruth, she'll help.
我不用人帮
I won't need any help.
我没事的
I'll be fine.
我们没事的
We'll be fine.
你觉得呢
What you think?
你会没事吗
You gonna be fine?
我猜你回来露丝小姐挺高兴
I expect Miss Ruth happy you're back.
你失踪她很难过
Took it hard the day you gone missin'.
也一直在照顾那个男孩
Got her hands full with that boy, too.
我猜她发现你娶了妻
I expect she won't be none too happy
不会太高兴
she find out you got yourself a new woman.
还生了孩子
New baby, too.
又一个女人来找你麻烦了
Uh-oh. Here come your other woman problem.
埃兰为找你被害了
Elam went after you and got his self killed!
埃兰向来我行我素
Elam went his own way, as always.
伊娃  冷静
Eva, calm down now!
你消失了  他去找你
You disappeared and he went after you,
向来都是
as always!
伊娃  对不起
Eva, I'm sorry.
道歉不能让他死而复生
Sorry ain't gonna bring him back.
好了  快上车  伙计们
All right, load 'em up, children!
你们浪费的可是我的时间
That my daylight you burnin' here!
我没开玩笑
And I ain't cookin' up no more.
我很好奇博汉南先生既然回来了
I'm curious to know if Mr. Bohannon will resume
是否会继续担任总工程师
his role as chief engineer now that he's returned.
不  德莱尼先生才是总工程师
No, Mr. Delaney is chief engineer now
未来也会是
and will be for the foreseeable future.
华盛顿方面没向你
You don't expect any political pressure
政治施压  让博汉南复职吗
from Washington to restore Bohannon to his post?
没有  何出此言
No, why?
因为他救了一个小男孩的命
He saved a young boy's life?
全国人民都将他视为英雄
People around the country view him as a hero.
政府最爱英雄人物
Washington loves a hero.
英雄和迷途羔羊
There is a difference between a hero
是有区别的  埃里森小姐
and a man who's lost his way, Miss Ellison--
似乎政府和你都无法理解
Something Washington nor you seem to understand.
如果不知情
If I didn't know better,
我或许会以为你对博汉南的好奇
I might mistake your obsession with Bohannon
另有更...
for something more, uh...
私人的原因
personal.
他没那么有趣
He's not that interesting.
抱歉  埃里森小姐  我...
Excuse me, Miss Ellison. I, uh--
那是怀俄明的新州旗
That's the flag of the new Wyoming territory.
为什么竖在那
Odd place for it.
当人们乘着你的火车来这
One day when people arrive on your train,
他们会抬头看到那面旗子
They'll look up, see that flag flyin'
在我的议会大楼上飘扬
above my statehouse,
并且明白我们在这建立法律和秩序的价值所在
and know the value we place on law and order around here.
法律会保护强占
Law abiding people who admire the confiscation
私人财产的人吗
of private property, hmm?
那块地归铁路所有
That's railroad land.
严格来说  如果没有进行
Technically, if it's not in use by the railroad
铁路建设相关活动  那么那块地
for railroad purposes, that land is available
就可以被国家收购
for acquisition by the state under eminent domain.
这是法律规定  杜兰特先生
That's the law, Mr. Durant.
你对法律的私自解释
I will not be intimidated
威胁不了我  坎贝尔先生
by your interpretation of law, Mr. Campbell.
还有前些天  你手下的执法者
Nor by the hanging shenanigans of your lawmen
在赌场绞死人的鬼把戏
in the casino a few days ago.
那块地是联太公司
Now, that land's the future site
食品仓库的未来选址
of the Union Pacific food depot.
我们谈话的时候  我的工程师已经在规划了
My engineers are drawing up plans even as we speak.
如果二十四小时内那小山上还看不到建筑构架
If there is no structure on that hill within 24 hours,
杜兰特先生  我的办公室就会提交0939号表格
Mr. Durant, my office will file form 0939,
宣布那块土地属于国家财产
condemning that property for state use...
这是《美国铁路法案》的规定
as set forth by the United States Railroad Act.
我同意  坎贝尔先生
Fair enough, Mr. Campbell.
我同意
Fair enough.
坎贝尔先生
Mr. Campbell.
埃里森小姐
Miss Ellison.
颜色真不错
That's a lovely color.
什么
Excuse me?
我是说你的裙子
On you, that is.
谢谢
Thank you.
请允许我...
Allow me.
我自己可以走
Oh, I can manage on my own.
谢谢
Thank you.
明早之前  我要在教堂东边的山顶
I need half a dozen of my chicken coops on the hill
建六个鸡舍
just east of the church by tomorrow morning.
需要多少人力和材料尽管用
Divert whatever manpower and supplies you need.
我刚派了第二班工人去开山
I just put a second shift on the grade.
是你的命令
Per your orders.
谢谢啦  格兰特
Oh, well, thank you, Delaney.
完工时通知我一声
Let me know when it's done.
你迟到了
You're late.
也称法老牌戏  一种法国扑克游戏  规则复杂
你在这开设了法罗牌局
You playin' Faro in here now?
不关你的事  伊娃
I don't see how that's any business of yours, Eva.
赌最后三张牌要多少钱
How much does the last three cards pay?
去擦桌子
Clean the tables.
你不会想着在我的赌场里赌一把吧
You ain't thinkin' of gambling in my casino now?
正有此意
Uh...Yeah.
我正想赌一把  米奇
I'm thinkin' I will, Mickey.
你会输掉一切的
You could lose everything.
我没什么可输的了
I got nothin' left to lose.
那我给你些小建议
Small bit of advice then.
离法罗牌桌远点
Stay away from the Faro table.
牌盒有诈
The box is rigged.
伙计们  下午好
Afternoon, fellas.
你迷路了吗  小姑娘
You, uh, lost little lady?
为什么这么说
Why?
你们看不上我的钱吗
My money ain't good enough for ya?
我看得上
It's good enough for me.
想听听我丢掉头皮的故事吗
You want to hear the story of how I lost my scalp?
别再讲了  华莱士
Not again, Wallace.
算我一个
Deal me in.
我很乐意
My pleasure.
-谢谢  -是的  先生
- Thank you. - Yes, sir.
我叫博汉南
Name's Bohannon.
是的  先生
Yes, sir.
你们有谁被大猎犬追过吗
Any you all ever been chased by a bloodhound?
-我们听说过  -是吗
- We familiar. - Yeah, well,
谢尔曼将军向海边行军时  他跟士兵说
On Sherman's march to the sea, he told his men,
"只要你遇到大猎犬就毙了它们"
he said, "You come across any bloodhounds, you shoot 'em", Right?
所以他们到了萨凡纳
So, they get to Savannah.
一位年轻士兵走在大街上
And this real green private, he's walkin' down the street
看到一位女士遛着贵宾犬
and he sees this lady walking with a poodle.
你懂的  戴着蝴蝶结和装饰的小狗
You know, bows in its hair and everything.
他看着贵宾犬  拔出枪  一枪爆头
One look at the poodle, pulls out his gun. Right in the head.
谢尔曼将军冲到他面前说
Sherman comes runnin' up to him,
"孩子  你为什么打死那只贵宾犬"
Says "Son, why'd you kill that poodle?"
这位士兵说  "长官
And the private says "Sir, well,
因为你不知道它们长大了会变成什么样"
on account of you--you never what they're gonna grow into."
好笑吧
Come on.
贵宾犬是什么
What's a poodle?
一共9美元23美分
That'll be 9.00 dollars and 23 cents.
现金或者代金券都可以
We take cash or scrip.
我能赊账吗
Can I get credit?
不能
No credit.
如果你没有现金或代金券
If you ain't got cash nor scrip,
我就不能卖给你
I can't sell you nothin'.
但我需要这些东西
But I need these things.
我也要做生意营生
And I got a business to run.
没事的  阿德勒先生
That's all right, Mr. Adler.
我来帮博汉南夫人付账吧
I'll take care of Mrs. Bohannon's sundries today.
我肯定博汉南先生没什么意见的
I'm sure Mr. Bohannon is good for it.
好的  坎贝尔先生
Yes, sir, Mr. Campbell.
悉听尊便
Whatever you say.
我加注
I'm raise ya.
好的  姑娘
All right, young lady.
我跟
Call.
满堂红
Full house.
对Q和对10
Queens over 10s.
慢着点
Whoa whoa whoa whoa whoa, easy now.
别急
Not so fast.
打败一位女士确实很难
You know, it really is hard to beat a lady.
除非你是国王[有K]
Unless you're a king.
你是怎么做到的
But how did-- how'd you do that?
不  不可能的
No, that ain't right.
别哭  输钱而已
Don't cry. It's only money.
你好  女士
Howdy, ma'am.
我不是来要钱的  我发誓
I don't want my money back, I swear.
我只想知道你是如何出千骗我的
I just want to know how you cheated me.
你自己骗了自己
You cheated yourself, woman,
和我这种人坐到一桌
By sittin' down at a table with the likes of me.
你要么就是绝望
Now, you are either desperate,
贪婪
greedy,
要么就是愚蠢
or stupid.
我是绝望了
I'm just desperate.
而且愚蠢
And stupid.
我想知道你是如何做到的
And I need to know how you did it.
对于不会使用的人来说
That's dangerous knowledge
那是危险的本领
for someone who don't know how to use it.
我知道如何使用
I know how to use it.
诀窍全在手上
It's all in the grip.
比如说有人在出千
Now, say if someone were to cheat...
拇指  指尖
thumb, fingertips.
Thumb, fingertips.
教我
Teach me.
教你我花了多年练会的本领
What took me years to perfect?
我可不傻
I ain't stupid.
我会报答你的
I'll make it worth your while.
用双倍的火药
Double the powder on those charges.
明白  先生
Yes, sir.
那么多的炸药会害死我们的
That much powder's likely to get us all killed.
管事的决定我们用多少炸药
Boss man decide how much powder we use.
你现在不是管事的了
You ain't boss man no more.
德莱尼先生
Mr. Delaney.
那块石头
That rock?
属于页岩
It's shale.
有页岩的地方就会有沼气
Where there's shale, there's methane.
你放两倍火药
You double that powder,
碎片很可能会害死
shrapnel's likely to kill every man
离山壁大约一百码内的所有人
within about a hundred yards of that wall right there.
回去工作  博汉南
Get back to work, Bohannon.
如果我想要你的建议  我会问的
I want your advice, I'll ask for it.
好吧  把那些桌子翻过来
All right. Turn them tables over,
在爆炸前躲到后面
get behind 'em before that thing blows.
我可不想夹在两个白人之间难做事
You know I ain't one to come between two feudin' white men.
你更不想死
You don't want to die, neither.
动手  把它们转过来
Do it! Turn 'em over!
点燃引线
Light those fuses.
博汉南先生  你快要拿回你的职位了
Mr. Bohannon, you about to get your job back.
黑火药
妈的
Shit!
你想干嘛
What do you want?
我不知道埃兰去找我了
I didn't know Elam'd gone lookin' for me.
你像那样消失
You shoulda known you'd disappear like that,
他当然会去找你
he's gonna come lookin'.
我没有消失  我被抓走了
I didn't disappear. I was took.
被武装人员绑架了
By armed men against my will.
但那时他不听我的
But by then he wasn't listenin' to me.
我一直有梦见
I've been havin' dreams...
埃兰
about Elam.
不是每晚  但也差不多了
Not every night, but most nights.
我在一个大城市的某处
I'm in a big city somewheres.
芝加哥
Chicago.
纽约
New York.
我迷路了
I'm lost.
在街道上走着
Walkin' the streets.
看着人们的家
Lookin' into peoples' homes.
那些美好温暖的窗户
Their nice warm windows.
我却在外面
I'm on the outside.
一直在外面
Always on the outside.
所有人都怕我
Everyone's afraid of me.
我想是因为我的刺青
I think it's 'cause of my tattoo.
之后我才意识到
And then I realize...
并不是这个原因
that's not what it is.
我看到了我的倒影
I see my reflection.
我不再是我了
I'm not me anymore.
我变成了一头熊  在寻找埃兰
I'm a bear, and I'm lookin' for Elam.
那只是个梦  伊娃
Thems is just dreams, Eva.
没有任何意义
They don't mean nothin'.
他把你当作朋友  博汉南先生
He considered you a friend, Mr. Bohannon.
我想那对你还是有些意义的
I expect that might mean somethin' to ya,
我知道你没有多少朋友
since I know you ain't had many.
那么...
Well...
现在又少了一个
one fewer now.
联太公司的托马斯·杜兰特先生
Mr. Thomas Durant of the Union Pacific
不是我们碰到的第一个
is not the first person we've run into
与我意见相左的人
who didn't see things my way.
确实不是  先生
No, sir.
过来
Come here!
如果人们相信他们中有人能凌驾于法律之上
If people believe any one of them is above the law,
那法律就形同虚设
there will be no law.
你是说杜兰特吗
Durant?
我想问问韦伯法官关于重建的意见
I'd like to ask Judge Webber his opinion on a remedy.
这个点  你应该能在赌场
This hour, you're likely to find him
或者妓院里找到他
at the Faro Tables or the whorehouse.
是  先生
Yes, sir.
走开  走开
Get off! Get off!
今天怎么样  丈夫
How was your day, husband?
还不错
It was fine.
-你呢  -还行吧
- Yours? - Just fine.
博汉南先生
Mr. Bohannon.
你在里面吗
You in there?
博汉南先生
Mr. Bohannon.
坎贝尔州长
Governor Campbell.
很高兴再次见到你  博汉南太太
Why, it's nice to see you again, Mrs. Bohannon.
如果你有话要对我妻子说
You got somethin' to say to my wife, son,
跟我说就行了
you talk to me.
我只是想说我给她买了顿饭
I bought her a meal is all.
你喜欢吗
How you enjoyin' it?
我可以自己买
I can buy my own meals.
你昨天跟我的人发生了冲突
You handled yourself mightily with my men yesterday.
我跟他们说过了  我不想找麻烦
Like I told 'em, I ain't lookin' for trouble.
各位晚安
Y'all have a good night.
格兰特将军非常看重你  博汉南先生
General Grant holds you in high regard, Mr. Bohannon.
你想怎么样
What do you want?
像你这种身份的人却混迹于一帮...
A man of your stature livin' amongst the, uh...
黑鬼吗
Negros?
自由人
Freedmen.
你没必要住在这种肮脏的地方  博汉南先生
Now, you don't have to live in squalor, Mr. Bohannon.
你为我工作  我会给你体面的工资
You work for me. I'll pay you a decent wage.
我已经有工作了
I already got a job.
我会付你铺铁轨的三倍工资
I'll pay you three times what you make layin' rail.
还会为你的家人建一所房子
And I'll help you build a house for your family.
在那之前  请允许我为你在旅馆订个房间
Until then, allow me to engage a room for you at the hotel.
热水澡  暖和的床
Hot bath, warm bed.
你今晚就可以过去  博汉南太太
You could be there tonight, Mrs. Bohannon.
为投机者工作吗
Work for a carpetbagger?
绝对不可能
Not a chance in a hell.
先生  我相信日后人们
The Freedmen's Bureau, sir, is but one legacy
会因自由民局而记住我
of reconstruction I believe I shall be remembered for.
格兰特建立的机构  旨在帮助黑人  促进黑人和白人合作
并爱戴我
And fondly.
如果你改变主意的话  来找我
Should you change your mind.
我数了一下  我们到这之后
By my count, that's two good jobs
你已经拒绝了两份好工作
that you've turned down since we got here.
我们接下来该怎么办
What're we meant to do then?
娜奥米
Naomi...
我所做的一切
Everything I done...
我杀过的人  带来的毁灭
all the death and destruction I put my hand to
和承受过的痛苦
and was put to me--
如果不建完这条铁路  这些都将沦为徒劳
all that is for naught if I don't finish this road.
博汉南先生
Mr. Bohannon.
没想到你居然还在这里
Surprised you're still here.
我也是
Likewise.
这里确实有种魔力
Somethin' about the place.
这里的菜很好  毫无疑问
The cuisine, no doubt.
我以为你早就逃回纽约了
Thought you would have hightailed it back to New York by now.
故事把我留在了这里
Story keeps me here.
小心别让故事害死你
Careful it don't kill ya.
你还没被害死呢
Hasn't killed you.
暂时没有
Yet.
我听说你结婚了
I hear you got married.
是的
Yeah.
摩门淑女
Nice mormon girl.
我对你的故事很感兴趣  博汉南先生
I'm interested in your story, Mr. Bohannon.
我的读者也是
My readers will be as well.
这不是故事  埃里森小姐
Ain't a story, Miss Ellison.
只是生活而已
Just a life.
自己的生活自己过  没必要让别人读
It's mine to live, nobody's to read about.
我
Oh, I...
抱歉打扰你们用餐
Sorry to interrupt your supper.
我想过来打个招呼
Thought I should come by and say howdy.
我们以为你死了
We thought you were dead.
你们为什么这么想
Why'd you think that?
不然你会回来的
You would have come back otherwise.
去外面等着  孩子
Why don't you go wait outside, boy.
去吧
Go on.
以斯拉很想你  博汉南先生
Ezra has missed you, Mr. Bohannon.
他为你哀伤
He grieved for you.
我也是
As did I.
你把他带得很好  他长高了
You done right by him. He's growin' up tall.
是的
Yes.
我们俩现在相依为命
We're our own little family now.
只有我们俩
The two of us.
露丝
Ruth--
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
现在你回来了
Now you're back.
带着新妻儿
With a new wife and child.
我相信随着铁路向前铺
I'm sure as the railroad starts moving,
你也会跟着一起走
You'll be moving with it.
我要照料教堂
I have my church to look after.
还有那孩子
And the boy.
我们会留在这里
We'll be staying here.
我来是想求你帮忙
I come to ask a favor.
我觉得我帮不上你什么
I don't think I can help you.
娜奥米和我儿子  威廉
Naomi and my boy, William...
我去挖路基时  他们没人照顾
When I'm out in the cut, they're here all alone.
我知道你看不惯
I know how you feel.
摩门教徒
About Mormons.
我希望如果需要的话
I was hopin' you could find it in your heart
你能发发善心
to lend a hand.
伸出援手
If need be.
我建立这座教堂的目的就是为贫苦之人
I have built the walls of my church to be a stronghold
提供一个避风港  博汉南先生
for the needy, Mr. Bohannon.
如果某天你的妻儿来到了教堂门前
Should your wife and child ever find themselves at my door,
正如对镇里的任何人一样
they, like everyone else in this town,
教堂大门会向他们敞开
will find it open.
这些都不是你的错  孩子
You know, ain't none of this your fault, son.
你用自己换了我
You traded yourself for me.
拜托
Come on.
换你也会这样做
You would have done the same.
总之  谢谢你
Anyways, thank you.
不客气
You're welcome.
*他与我漫步*
*And he walks with me*
*他与我谈天*
*And he talks with me*
*他说我是主的孩子*
*And he tells me I am his own*
*我们在那里*
*And the joy we share*
*分享的快乐*
*As we tarry there*
*永远无人知*
*No other has ever known*
卡伦·博汉南起死回生
被解职的总工程师重回夏安镇
The defrocked chief engineer's return to Cheyenne
意味着这场已进行了一半的游戏中
means another actor has entered the play,
又多了一位玩家
already half finished.
我们有一位言过其实的梦想家
With the bombastic dreamer,
他的成败取决于铁路能否完工
his legacy depending on completing this road.
我们还有一位投机官僚
And the carpetbagging bureaucrat,
他负责将文明带到一片
tasked with bringing civilization to a land
昨日还以蛮荒和自由为豪的土地
that, just yesterday, boasted wild and free.
卡伦·博汉南  笔者仍感到很费解
Cullen Bohannon, for reasons this reporter has yet to divine,
他似乎坚定地要建成铁路
seems determined to see this road through.
不管他是劳工还是老板
Whether he does it as laborer or boss,
生还是死
alive or dead,
时间会告诉我们一切  亲爱的读者
Only time will tell, dear reader.
时间会告诉我们一切
Only time will tell.
*他与我漫步  他与我谈天*
*He walks with me and he talks with me*
*他说我是主的孩子*
*And he tells me I am his own*
*我们在那里  分享的快乐*
*And the joy we share as we tarry there*
*永远无人知*
*No other has ever known*